[Music]
right I'm doing this one a little lately
today I was writing something else I
came up this Nickelback Yonsei now G um
so Nickelback is the band that everybody
loves to hate it's the butt of jokes
that Nickelback is an unlikable band
whereas Beyonce's our queen and
everyone's supposed to like Beyonce
there are people in society that like
things simply because they're popular
and there's also people who only like
things because they're unpopular they
like what is not popular what is unique
and different and both of those things
are reflection of society you're looking
at society and then deciding whether or
not you like it or not it's like oh it's
top 40 I can't possibly like it or like
without actually looking and saying do I
like it and so that to me is the
difference I'm pretty mint on Nickelback
and Beyonce they're not either of them
my favorite nor do I hate either of them
but the question is to look inside and
say okay is it do I like this song or do
I not like this song
because at every Nickelback concert if
they still do concerts I don't know that
there's probably people who would be
there and like their music but don't
want other people to know that they like
their music so they're not selling seats
that they could be selling likewise at a
Beyonce concert with her because she's
super popular really expensive tickets
there are people sitting there that are
mad about her but they're dressed there
because it's what you're supposed to
like they're supposed to like Beyonce so
they're there in both ways it's not
creating the greatest happiness and I
have my own version of Beyonce that this
could be a bread that could be brought
in I went to go see Jane Goodall a
couple years ago and the tickets because
it was this tiny tiny little venue it
tickets for like $300 so it was like my
entire entertainment budget for the year
to go and see her and I'm glad that I
spent it it was on my bucket list and I
got to meet her and get her to sign a
book but when I went there I was like
okay this is like for other people that
are sitting there not that they didn't
love Jane Goodall but they had like
their kid and their
friend with them I'm like oh this is a
regular night out for you so when we
price things simply on if you can afford
it then you must like it more which is
kind of where our economics is based on
but that's not the truth because there
are people there that it was just
another night out for it wasn't on their
bucket list it wasn't jank at all but it
was like their ultimate hero was like
yeah I'll go see someone else on Tuesday
and someone else next week it's a and
there was probably people who like me
were as in love with Jane Goodall as I
am but couldn't afford a $300 ticket or
I mean I could if part of the real don't
take it either but I think there is a
way to price things so that it's about
the value like if you are Beyonce who do
you want at your concert the fans that
can pay the highest price yes because
you want to make money at it but if
you're not making money at all at it
would you rather have the fans that can
pay the highest price still or would you
rather have the fans that are the most
devoted and are they're gonna be the
happiest because you're there because
they're there so they're gonna be the
happiest because they get to see you
perform
and I think most artists would rather
have dedicated fans and so in the new
economic system not the first things we
create but wait further on and we don't
have if we don't have money if would you
get to the place where you don't have
currency I think that is what happens
artists first of all choose a venue
based on who's interested in coming so
if you have 100 devoted fans and a
thousand less devoted but but still fans
and then the myth people well the Met
people aren't going they're gonna be
choosing their top artists that they
want to go to and so you find a venue
that the hokies showcases those 1500
fans and that's the vendor urine
Beyonce's gonna have tens of thousands
and so finding a venue that works for
that might not work for every artist but
then there's broadcast you know
everything else likewise the artists
themselves can choose who they want to
give it to you so fans that are very
involved in their arts and and their
communicating with them social media
that's gonna be who they're gonna want
to give their tickets to and then causes
that they care about like hey the ocean
needs to get cleaned up so anyone who
comes up with that can give a hundred
tickets away or they can give a prize
people that there are other ways to have
incentives but just for me this
Nickelback versus Beyonce is very much
about if you're looking to the outside
world to decide what you like it's
already broken economics because it's
already our true diversity that saves us
is that we like different bands is that
we like different artists that we have
different partners that we want in
different activities because it's a lot
more easy to allocate in that kind of
economic system where we don't all like
the same singers so we don't all like to
play them the exact same city then a
society where it's it's like oh New York
live in New York just cuz it's New York
because every everyone's supposed to
want to live in New York um so I don't
know this little rambley today but see
mom